This "pestilent dust"
that counselor refers to
has appeared on only three occasions.
Each time it was tested,
and the results... limestone.
It's messy...
but innocuous.
Innocuous?
Defined by Webster's as harmless.
I know what it means.
May I? Thank you.
Your Honor...
imagine how the children
in this neighborhood
are being made to feel.
The constant pounding of construction
ringing in their ears,
as this skyscraper,
a tribute to mankind's greed,
grows daily,
casting an ominous shadow
over their lives,
filling them with dread
even as they are surrounded
by this toxic dust.
Your Honor, Kendall Construction
builds neighborhoods.
It doesn't destroy them.
Granting a restraining order against
this construction site will throw
753 Philadelphians out of work,
and lend validation
to this contemptible and groundless
nuisance suit.
It's an example of
the rapacious litigation
that today is tearing at
the very fabric of our society.
Let's not go off the deep end, gentlemen.
You've made an articulate
and compelling presentation,
Mr. Miller,
but I don't believe
you've proven irreparable harm.
Not yet, Your Honor.
9:42, whereas decedent...
Of trade name without...
Without complete approval.
Is that you?
Yeah, that's me.
Miller. Yes.
Hello, Iris.
Client of yours?
Funny!
Hold on, Iris. Excuse me, sir?
Uh, sir? Yo!
Yo!
My sons and I went
to a restaurant the other day.
We ordered coffee.
The waiter comes up and goes...
Here's the literature.
"Would you like sugar or Sweet 'N' Low?"
I said, "Do I look like
I should be on a diet?"
Oh, God.
Andy.
Hi, doc.
Your blood work came back this morning.
I'm going to come back
in a few minutes
and talk to you about it.
All right?
I'll be right here.
Good.
Hi.
How are you feeling?
Feeling pretty good.
Great.
Make a fist for me.
Once more.
Going to have to start
looking for veins
in your feet, sweetheart.
Patience, Tyrone.
Okay. Okay.
Once more.
Hey, cab.
Hey, Andy,
terrific job on the Kendall situation.
Top-notch, Mr. Beckett.
Thanks, Kenneth, Robert.
Hi, Mr. Beckett.
Hi, Rose. Anthea.
Just the paralegal extraordinaire
I was hoping to see.
I know what that means. The answer is no.
I'm talking dinner at Felicia's.
I've got a class.
I've got some pretty compelling briefs
that need proofing.
You can exploit somebody else.
Since you've asked...
Your exam.
Thank you. 98.
98?
98. Congratulations.
Hey.
I have to pick up Amy
from her after-school,
but I want to talk to you
about that Hansen thing.
Give me a call.
Tell Amy that I loved her painting.
It's on my wall.
Hi, Andrew. Conference call's up.
The roll call just started.
Now, this is the settlement agreement.
The red-line copy's
on your desk.
You need me in there?
No. It's 6:30. Go home.
Hello?
Hey, Mom.
Oh, hi, darling.
What a wonderful surprise.
How are you?
Good.
Well, what does Dr. Gillman say?
Dr. Gillman says I am fine.
My blood work is excellent.
She says my T-cells are steady.
Honey, how about your platelets?
What did she say?
Even my platelets look good.
Great.
Mom, more importantly, how are you?
Mom?
I...
I'm fine.
And how's Dad?
Dad is fine.
And what are you doing?
Okay.
"Action for the wrongful interference
with prospective economic relations."
Okay.
Andy?
Yo?
Am I interrupting you?
Uh, in a word, Bob...
Charles wants to see you upstairs.
I was just about to take a break.
You're sure I'm not
under-dressed for this?
No, no, you're not.
Charles,
Andy has expressed a keen interest
in Highline versus Sander Systems.
Isn't that right, Andy?
The fate of the participants
interests me.
Yes, sir.
It's an antitrust action.
It is...
and it isn't, Charles.
Sander Systems copies
Highline's spreadsheet program.
For me,
the legal principle involved
is copyright infringement.
Hmm.
Well, tell me this, Andy.
Which side of this conflict
would you wish to see emerge victorious?
And don't allow my close,
personal relationship
with Bill Wright, Sander Systems' CEO,
to influence your answer in any way.
I'd like to see Highline win this one.
Oh. Why, Beckett?
If Sander Systems wins,
an energetic, young company
is destroyed.
The laws for antitrust and copyright
were enacted to prevent
exactly the kind of bullshit
that Sander Systems is trying to pull.
Andy, you know who reps Highline?
Rodney Bailey.
Oh, I object.
Rodney Bailey,
who couldn't find his way
around copyright law
with a map.
Well, apparently,
the fellas at Highline
agree with you, Andy,
which explains why,
as of 9:03 this evening,
right after the dessert course,
Highline, Inc.
Is now represented
by Wyant, Wheeler, Hellerman,
Tetlow & Brown...
Outstanding.
And more specifically,
senior associate Andrew Beckett.
Bravo!
Yes!
Yeah!
Congratulations.
Thank you, Robert. Thank you.
Now, we've got to get
on Highline right away.
Statute of limitations.
Yeah, I'm right on it.
10 days before we have to file.
Tokyo on line four, Bob.
Walter, thank you.
Thank you.
Kenneth, thank you.
You bet, Andy. Congratulations.
Aw, thanks.
I'm overwhelmed.
What's that on your forehead, pal?
What? Where?
That, right there on your forehead.
Oh, I got whacked in the head
with a racquetball.
Ooh.
Excuse me.
Charles, I...
I sincerely appreciate
your faith in my abilities.
Faith, Andy,
is a belief in something
for which we have no evidence.
It does not apply to this situation.
Well, go home.
Oh, no! Go back to work.
Yeah. Yeah.
Thank you, Charles.
No sweat, buddy.
The committee meeting
planned for next week.
Staff members...
Tommy, how are you?
The Highline complaint
is right there on my desk, Shelby.
It's all set to go,
so make sure Jamey is on top of it.
Sure, you got it.
Anything else?
No. No, that's it.
I'm going to be working
out of the house here
for the rest of the afternoon,
so thanks a lot.
Bye, bye.
Okay, now, you're going to want
to apply this foundation
as evenly as you can.
Mm-hmm.
Because you don't want it to look like
you threw it on with a spoon...
Yeah.
So over here, you try this.
I got it.
Right there.
Chandra, you don't think this is
just a little too orange for me?
Well, okay, it's Tahitian bronze,
and that works best
on these lesions, okay?
Think of it as
the "I just got back from Aruba" look.
Exactly.
I've called in sick for four days,
and now they're going to think
that I was taking a cruise.
Fax.
Thank you, Bruno.
Here, okay, look.
We can try this light Egypt...
Ah, ow.
What?
Oh, ow.
Andy?
Excuse me.
Just like my cousin Fredo.
Hi.
Does anybody want a bagel?
You okay, Andy?
I think...
I think I need to go to the hospital.
Watch out!
Hello, hello.
Oh...
It's all right.
I'm getting out of here.
Okay.
I'll talk to you later.
Oh, one more, one more.
Thank you for driving
like a bat out of hell.
Take it easy, all right?
Dr. Gillman
is out of her office.
I told her to take a day off
and she took a day off.
Can you believe that?
So they took blood?
A specimen or something?
Blood, yes.
A specimen, I'm empty.
Did you find somebody to take your class?
Don't worry about it.
Let me see.
Oh, you got a fever, baby.
Oh, there's my guy. Excuse me.
Uh, doctor? Hello, hi.
Just one second.
I came that close to not making it
into the bathroom again.
I almost lost it in front of everybody.
Well, so what?
It's nothing to be ashamed of.
I'm not ashamed, it's just...
Oh, uh...
Uh, what about my blood work?
We're waiting.
Meanwhile, I want to prep you
for a colonoscopy.
We want to take a look inside.
It sounds delightful.
Wait a minute, wait a minute.
Why you need to do this?
Who are you?
Who are you, uh, Dr., uh...
This is my partner.
Yeah?
Uh, he keeps records
of my hospital visits.
It's nothing personal.
Oh, I'm Dr. Klenstein.
Listen, you're right.
A colonoscopy
is not a pleasant procedure,
but if the KS is causing the diarrhea,
we've got to know
about that right away.
No, no, no.
It could be parasites,
an infection, I mean...
Reaction to the AZT.
All of these are possibilities,
but we've got to go forward...
Listen to me.
He's not going through
some painful procedure
until we've canceled out
everything else.
You know what I mean?
Listen, I'm trying
to help your partner, okay?
And you're not a member
of his immediate family.
I'm not.
I could have you removed from the ER.
Really?
Look, look, look. He's upset. He's sorry.
No, don't apologize for me, okay?
Okay, he's not sorry.
Let's do this.
Let's find out
what the blood work tells us,
I will try to give you
a specimen...
some hospital food may help me along...
and then we might hear from Dr. Gillman,
and we can start from there.
Okay? Everybody happy?
All right?
I'll get on the lab
about the blood work.
Thank you, doctor.
I'm sorry.
Oh, that's...
that's the third time
the office has beeped me.
I better go.
Klenstein.
I've got to give them a call.
I want you to sit down,
and I want you to relax.
I am relaxed.
Oh, good, good.
Is there a phone around
somewhere nearby?
Down the hall.
Thank you.
If you or someone you know
has been injured
through the fault of others,
you may be entitled
to a tax settlement or money damages
for your pain and suffering.
Good Lord.
I'm attorney Joseph Miller...
Mr. Beckett's office.
Shelby, it's me.
Jamey's been beeping me.
Oh, I'm so glad you called, Andrew.
Listen, I just want to let you know
we have a minor catastrophe
in the making here.
It's about that Highline complaint.
Jamey is going absolutely ballistic.
All right, all right.
Calm down. Put him on.
One second.
Andy, this is a disaster.
We can't find the revisions
on the Highline complaint.
Well, wait, wait, wait.
Slow down, slow down.
Okay. I told them you were
working on it at home,
and it was supposed to be here
this morning.
No, no.
I brought it into the office
last night.
I was there till 3:00 A.M.
There should be a copy
with corrections on my desk.
I'm telling you,
it's not here, Andy.
Shelby can't find it, either.
All right.
Uh...
the hard disk on my computer.
Print it up on the double
and run it through
word processing yourself.
Okay, what did you file it under?
H-L-1.
Jamey, I don't have to remind you, do I,
that we are up against
the statute of limitations
on this complaint?
And it runs out in...
in...
in 75 minutes.
It's not here, Andy.
Not there? I'm on my way.
Every problem has a solution.
Push, baby. Push.
Push.
Oh, it's coming.
Yeah, baby, it's coming.
It's...
It's a girl.
It's a girl. Oh, my God.
Oh, my God.
Take a picture, Joe.
I'm trying.
I can't get the film in there.
Oh, my God.
Help me, baby.
Oh, look at her, look at her.
Look at our baby.
That little, sweet little...
Get her before she gets too old.
Oh, my God.
She's perfect, Lisa.
She has long hair.
Yeah, go down
to Famous 4th Street Deli,
get a pound of Scotch salmon.
She likes that Scotch salmon.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
You know, some onion rolls, bagels.
Here, give me a call.
Onion rolls, bagels.
Yeah, champagne, nice champagne. Yeah.
You're that TV guy.
I don't care how much it costs.
Get some nice Dom Perignon.
Thank you.
How much? Oh, $100.
No, don't get me Dom Perignon.
Get a nice Californian.
Dom Perignon's too much.
Get it all over here,
because she's starving.
No, no, Iris, not the baby.
Lisa is starving.
Yeah, Lisa.
Iris, Iris, Iris, Iris, listen.
Anybody call?
An Andrew Beckett called.
Beckett?
Who's Andrew Beckett?
There he is! Joseph!
Hey! Hey!
All right, look,
I want you to explain this to me
like I'm a 6-year-old, okay?
The entire street is clear
except for one small area
under construction,
this huge hole that is clearly
marked and blocked off.
Yes.
You decide you must cross the street
at this spot, no other.
You fall into the hole.
Now you want to sue the city
for negligence, right?
Yes. Do I have a case?
Yes.
Yeah, of course you've got a case.
Great.
I want you to go
with my assistant Iris here.
She'll have you fill out some forms,
tell you all about our fee arrangement.
Of course, you know we take no cash
unless we get cash justice for you.
Uh-huh. How's your back?
You got any lower back pain,
dizziness, nightmares?
Funny you should mention that...
Iris will take good care of you.
Iris, you take good care of Mr. Finley.
I will.
Mr. Beckett's here.
Hey, thanks a lot.
Thank you very, very much.
All right, take care.
Mr. Beckett?
Mr. Beckett, come in.
It's good to see you again, counselor.
Judge Tate.
Kendall Construction.
Innocuous.
How are you?
What happened to your face?
I have AIDS.
Oh.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I, uh...
Can I sit down?
Yeah.
Thank you.
Oh, look at this.
You have a new baby.
Yeah.
A little baby girl.
Oh, "It's a girl."
Congratulations.
Yeah. One week old.
Kids are great.
Yeah, thank you, Beckett.
I'm real excited about it.
Listen, I, uh...
What can I do for you?
I've, uh...
I've been fired
by Wyant-Wheeler.
I plan on bringing
a wrongful termination suit
against Charles Wheeler
and his partners.
You want to sue Wyant, Wheeler,
Hellerman, Tetlow & Brown?
Correct.
I'm seeking representation.
Continue.
I misplaced an important complaint.
That's their story.
Want to hear mine?
How many lawyers you go to
before you called me?
Nine.
Continue.
The night before it was due,
I worked on the complaint
in my office.
I left a copy of it on my desk.
The next day,
the complaint vanished.
No hard copy.
All traces of it
mysteriously gone from my computer.
Miraculously,
a copy of the complaint
was located at the last minute,
and we got it to court on time,
but the next day,
I was summoned to a meeting
with the managing partners.
They were waiting for me
in the conference room.
Oh, hello, Andy. Come on in.
Would you mind hitting the windows?
Thanks.
Hey, come on in, come on in.
Robert, Charles, Walter and Lydia.
Thanks for coming in.
Oh, of course.
Andy, before we begin,
I'd just like to say
that everyone in this room
is your friend.
I know that, Charles.
More than your friend.
Family.
Charles, I must apologize again
for the Highline mishap yesterday.
That was some scary moment
around here.
Wow, thank God the complaint was found
and no damage was done.
This time.
What about next time?
There won't be a next time.
I guarantee it.
Yeah.
It's just that something's
come over you lately, Andy.
I don't know.
Some kind of stupor or fogginess.
Some people think you have
an attitude problem, Beckett.
Really?
Who thinks that?
I do.
Excuse me.
Am I being fired?
Let me put it this way, Andy.
Your place in the future of this firm
is no longer secure.
We feel it isn't fair to keep you here
when your prospects are limited...
and now, I don't want to rush you out.
We've got a committee meeting.
Excuse me, Charles.
With all due respect, this...
this is preposterous.
It doesn't make any sense.
Oh, you're right, Beckett.
You don't have an attitude problem.
Take it easy, Walter.
If you had lost confidence in me,
why did you give me the Highline suit?
Andy, you nearly blew the entire case,
for chrissakes.
That alone is inexcusable.
It would've been catastrophic for us.
Uh-huh.
So you were concealing your illness?
That's correct.
All right, explain this to me
like I'm a 2-year-old, okay?
Because there's
an element to this thing
I just cannot get through
my thick head.
Didn't you have an obligation
to tell your employer
you had this dreaded,
deadly, infectious disease?
That's not the point.
From the day they hired me
to the day I was fired,
I served my clients
consistently, thoroughly,
with absolute excellence.
If they hadn't fired me,
that's what I'd be doing today.
And they don't want to fire you
for having AIDS,
so, in spite of your brilliance,
they make you look incompetent,
thus the mysterious lost files.
Is that what you're telling me?
Correct. I was sabotaged.
I don't buy it, counselor.
That's very disappointing.
I don't see a case.
I have a case.
If you don't want it for personal reasons...
Thank you.
That's correct, I don't.
Well, thank you
for your time, counselor.
Mr. Beckett?
Uh...
I'm sorry about what happened to you.
It's a bitch, you know?
Have a nice day, Mr. Beckett.
What the hell's
the matter with that guy?
Iris, find out
if Armbruster can see me.
Joe Miller's office.
Iris... find out
if Armbruster can see me.
Armbruster? When?
Sometime this afternoon.
No, right away, Iris.
Right away, Iris.
Okay.
Excuse me.
The HIV virus
can only be transmitted through
the exchange of bodily fluids,
namely, blood, semen,
and vaginal secretions.
Right, yeah,
but isn't it true
that they're finding out
all kinds of new things
about this disease every day?
All right, now, you tell me today
there's no danger, go home.
I go home,
I pick up my little baby girl,
then I find out
six months from now on the news,
whoops. Made a mistake.
Yeah, you can carry it
on your shirt or your clothes, or...
What are you doing?
We're going to draw blood.
- Why are we going to do that?
- Joe.
Little Joe.
I've known you since you were a kid,
and I don't care a whit
about your private life.
Thanks, doc.
I don't need an AIDS test,
but thanks anyway.
Listen, just send a bill
to my office for me,
okay?
Thanks for the information. Really.
You have a problem with gays, Joe.
Not especially.
Yes, you do.
How many gays do you know?
How many do you know?
Lots.
Like who?
Karen Berman.
My Aunt Teresa.
Cousin Tommy
who lives in Rochester.
Eddie Meyers from the office.
Um, Stanley,
the guy who's putting in
our kitchen cabinets.
Aunt Teresa's gay?
That beautiful, sensuous,
voluptuous woman is a lesbian?
Duh.
Since when?
Probably since she was born.
Oh, man.
All right, well, hey,
I admit it, okay?
I'm prejudiced.
I don't like homosexuals.
There, you got me.
All right.
I mean, the way
these guys do that... thing.
Don't they get confused?
"I don't know, is that yours?
Is that mine?"
You know,
I don't want to be in the bed
with anybody who's stronger than me,
or has more hair on their chest
than I do.
Now, you can call me old-fashioned.
You can call me conservative.
Just call me a man.
Besides, I think you have
to be a man to understand how...
really disgusting
that whole idea is anyway.
Yeah? Yeah.
Well, well.
Little caveman of the house.
You damn skippy.
Here you go, baby.
Stay away from your Aunt Teresa too.
Joe, don't say that to her.
Think about it.
Those guys pumping up together,
trying to be macho and faggot
at the same time.
I can't stand that shit.
Hey, I'm being
totally honest with you, okay?
Oh, yeah, you are.
All right, I've got a question for you.
Would you accept a client
if you were constantly thinking,
"I don't want this person to touch me.
I don't want him
to even breathe on me"?
Not if I was you, honey.
That's what I'm talking about.
Mm-hmm.
What?
Ho, ho, ho!
Merry Christmas!
Merry Christmas.
Thank you.
Ho, ho, ho!
Hey, Merry Christmas.
Merry Christmas, sir.
Ho, ho, ho! Thank...
Happy New Year.
You're the, uh...
The TV guy.
Sir?
This is the supplement.
You're right.
There is a section
on HIV related discrimination.
Oh, thank you.
Thank you very much.
We do have a private
research room available.
I'm fine right here.
Thank you.
Excuse me.
Do you know where I can find
the State vs. Murdock case?
Just a moment.
I'll be right with you.
Wouldn't you be more comfortable
in a research room?
No.
Would it make you more comfortable?
Oh, uh...
Beckett.
How you doing?
Counselor.
Huh.
Whatever, sir.
Excuse me.
Who'd you get?
What?
Did you find a lawyer?
I'm a lawyer.
Hey, how's your baby?
Oh, yeah, she's...
She's wonderful, great.
What's her name?
Larice.
That's a beautiful name.
Named her after my sister.
Look, I'm, uh...
How'd they find out you have the AIDS?
One of the partners
noticed a lesion on my forehead.
Um...
but how do you go from...
How do you go from a lawyer
spotting a lesion,
which could've been anything,
to the partners deducing
that you have AIDS,
and terminating you
on the basis of that conclusion?
That's a good point.
The partner who spotted the lesion,
Walter Kenton,
worked for Walsh,
Ulmer & Brahm in D.C.
A paralegal there, Melissa Benedict,
she showed lesions on and off
for the better part of two, three years.
She says it was common knowledge
around the office
that her lesions were caused by AIDS.
But they didn't fire her.
No.
They did not fire her.
So you got a relevant precedent?
Mm-hmm.
The Arline decision.
Arline?
Supreme Court.
"The Federal Vocational
Rehabilitation Act
"of 1973 prohibits discrimination
"against otherwise qualified
handicapped persons
"who are able to perform
"the duties required by their employment.
"Although the ruling
"did not address the specific issue
of HIV and AIDS discrimination..."
"Subsequent decisions
have held that AIDS
"is protected as a handicap under law,
"not only because
of the physical limitations
"it imposes,
"but because the prejudice
"surrounding AIDS
exacts a social death which precedes..."
"Which precedes
the actual physical one."
"This is the essence of discrimination,
"formulating opinions about others
"not based on their individual merits,
"but rather
on their membership in a group
with assumed characteristics."
Charles Wheeler.
Julius Erving!
By golly, I'm glad to see you.
Ken Starr.
How are you?
It's only going to take a minute.
Charles Wheeler. How you doing?
How are you?
Very good, very good.
Summons for you.
Take a look at it.
Have a good day.
Hey, Dr. J., how are you?
I love you, man. You're the best.
You're the best.
If you ever need a lawyer for anything,
you give me a call.
If you slip and fall,
you know, accidents,
anything, let me know.
See you in court.
You're the TV guy.
Yeah, the TV guy.
Say, Chuck, what's up?
Now, regarding Andy,
I want to know everything
about his personal life.
Does he frequent those
pathetic bars on Chestnut Street?
Oh, Jesus.
What other homosexual facilities
does he go to?
Absolutely.
What deviant groups or organizations
does he secretly belong to?
Wait a minute.
Bob, what is it?
Let's make a fair settlement offer,
and put this whole
tragic business behind us.
Bob...
Andy brought AIDS into our offices,
into our men's room.
He brought AIDS
to our annual goddamn family picnic.
We ought to be suing him, Bob.
Where is your compassion, gentlemen?
Bob, we gave him Highline.
Did Andrew Beckett say,
"I might not be able
to serve our client
to the best of my ability"?
He said nothing,
and now, discarding
the trust and affection
I conferred upon him,
Andrew Beckett proposes
to haul me into court,
to sling accusations at me,
to call me a bigot...
in full view of the entire Philadelphia
judicial establishment.
My God.
Excuse me.
Beckett doesn't want to go to court.
He's looking for a quick,
tasty settlement.
A jury might decide that he has a case.
Wait a minute.
He was fired for incompetence,
not because he has AIDS.
You didn't know he was sick,
did you, Bob?
Holy shit. Did you, Bob?
No, no. Not really.
Okay, okay. Everybody...
Everybody, this is the house
that I grew up in.
Bonito.
Right here in the hometown
of Lower Merion, Pennsylvania.
Wait, here...
and here's proof.
There.
My handprints from
when I was a cute, little boy.
Today is the 40th wedding anniversary
of my mom and dad, the Becketts.
Isn't that something?
Pretty tough life around this poverty
so many years, huh?
Well, now, those can be mean streets.
Don't let appearances fool you.
Here's the front door.
Now, I once slammed
this finger in the front door
and I broke it.
Where's my brother?
Hey.
Hey, there's my sister Jill,
everybody.
Say hello, Alexis.
Mommy's pregnant again!
What?
Yes.
Are you really?
Hi, Meghan.
It's Uncle Andy.
Where's Dad?
He's out trying to get
the snow blower fixed.
It snows once in seven years,
Dad buys a new snow blower.
Oh, how are you?
Oh, Mom, today's a good day.
Meghan, keep that up.
You're doing a great job.
I got to say hello to the Brontë sisters.
How are you?
Good to see you.
Hi, Andy.
How are you?
Hey, hey, hey.
Put me down.
There's going to be
things said at the trial
that are going to be
hard for you to hear
about me and my personal life,
and there's going to be publicity.
I want to make sure
it's okay with everybody.
Andy, you want me to take her?
No, no.
She's...
she's fine.
I think it's great that you're asking,
Andy, but, uh...
this is really your call.
All right. Thank you, brother.
Thank you.
Hey, you're my kid brother.
That's all that matters, okay?
To be honest,
I'm worried about Mommy and Daddy.
They've been through so much already,
and it's possible that there are going
to be some very tough times ahead.
Uh, Andy, the way...
the way that you've
handled this whole thing,
you and Miguel, with so much courage,
I don't believe there's anything
that anyone could say
that would make us feel anything
but incredibly proud of you.
Well...
I didn't raise my kids
to sit in the back of the bus.
You get in there
and you fight for your rights, okay?
Gee, I love you guys.
Ladies and gentlemen of the jury...
forget everything
you've seen on television
and in the movies.
There's not going to be any
last-minute surprise witnesses.
Nobody's going to break down
on the stand
with a tearful confession.
You're going to be presented
with a simple fact.
Andrew Beckett was fired.
You'll hear two explanations
for why he was fired.
Ours...
and theirs.
It is up to you
to sift through
layer upon layer of truth
until you determine for yourselves
which version sounds the most true.
There are certain points
that I must prove to you.
Point number one,
Andrew Beckett was...
is...
a brilliant lawyer,
a great lawyer.
Point number two,
Andrew Beckett,
afflicted with a debilitating disease,
made the understandable, the personal,
the legal choice
to keep the fact of his illness
to himself.
Point number three,
his employers discovered his illness,
and, ladies and gentlemen,
the illness I'm referring to is AIDS.
Point number four,
they panicked.
And in their panic,
they did what most of us
would like to do with AIDS,
which is just get it and everybody
who has it as far away
from the rest of us as possible.
Now, the behavior
of Andrew Beckett's employers
may seem reasonable to you.
Does to me.
After all, AIDS is a deadly,
incurable disease,
but no matter how you come to judge
Charles Wheeler and his partners
in ethical, moral, and in human terms,
the fact of the matter is,
when they fired Andrew Beckett
because he had AIDS,
they broke the law.
Fact.
Andrew Beckett's performance
on the job
varied from competent, good,
to oftentimes mediocre,
to sometimes flagrantly incompetent.
Fact.
He claims he's the victim
of lies and deceit.
Fact.
It was Andrew Beckett who lied,
going to great lengths
to conceal his disease from his employers.
Fact.
He was...
successful in his duplicity.
The partners at Wyant-Wheeler
did not know
that Andrew Beckett had AIDS
when they fired him.
Fact.
Andrew Beckett is dying.
Andrew Beckett is angry...
because his lifestyle,
his reckless behavior,
has cut short his life.
And in his anger, his rage,
he is lashing out,
and he wants someone to pay.
Thank you.
Andrew Beckett
represented your company
in a lawsuit in 1990.
Is that correct?
That's correct.
Were you pleased with his work?
We were satisfied with the outcome
of the litigation.
Satisfied.
Mr. Laird,
when I approached you
about being a witness at this trial,
you gave sworn testimony
in a deposition,
is that correct?
That's correct.
In that deposition,
you said that you were,
"Impressed and delighted
with the quality
of Andrew Beckett's work."
Do you recall saying that?
In all honesty,
I was delighted
with certain aspects
of Andy's efforts,
but in general,
I found the work to be...
merely satisfactory.
Uh-huh.
Do you agree...
that a bologna sandwich
is a satisfactory meal,
whereas caviar and champagne,
roast duck and baked Alaska,
that might be considered
a delightful meal?
We object.
These gastronomical comments are
irrelevant to these proceedings, Your Honor.
They are not irrelevant.
Your Honor, five months ago,
this witness characterized
Andrew Beckett as caviar.
Now he's calling him
a bologna sandwich.
I think the jury is entitled to know
what powerful force
has caused him to change his mind.
He hasn't changed his mind.
He's amplified his answer.
Objection sustained.
All right.
All right, Mr. Laird,
explain this to me
like I'm a 4-year-old, okay?
Did Andrew Beckett
win your lawsuit for you?
Yes, we won.
Oh, congratulations.
That must've been a very...
satisfactory experience.
Homophobia's got to go!
Hey, hey! Ho, ho!
Homophobia's got to go.
Hey, hey, ho, ho!
Homophobia's got to go!
Ready, Mr. Beckett?
Get ready. Here they come.
No rights for sodomites!
It's Adam and Eve!
Not Adam and Steve!
Thou shalt not lie with mankind.
Do you see this as a gay rights issue?
I am not political.
I just want what is fair,
what is right.
But you are gay, aren't you?
I don't see how that's
any of your business,
but, yes, I am.
Totally irrelevant.
Doesn't matter.
Do you think that homosexuals
deserve special treatment?
Hell no.
We're standing here in Philadelphia,
the city of brotherly love,
the birthplace of freedom,
where the founding fathers authored
the Declaration of Independence.
And I don't recall
that glorious document
saying anything about
all straight men are created equal.
I believe it says,
"All men are created equal."
Give me a goddamn break.
As far as someone being fired
from a law firm or a business,
if we found that
their action was discriminatory,
they could no longer
do business with the city.
Thank you, mayor.
Joe.
Listen, you're, uh...
You're not getting a little light
in the sneakers, are you, pal?
Yeah, I am, Filko.
I'm, uh...
I'm changing.
I'm on the prowl,
and I'm looking for a hunk.
Not just any hunk.
I mean a man, a real man like you.
You can tell everybody about it.
You know what we do.
You want to play sailor?
You remember?
I'm Columbus, you're the first mate?
Knock if off.
That's not funny.
Let me tell you something.
These people make me sick, Filko,
but a law's been broken.
You remember the law, don't you?
At least we agree on one thing, Joe.
What's that, Charlie?
Tutti-fruttis make me sick too.
Ms. Benedict, is it true that you
worked for Walsh, Ulmer & Brahm
three years ago, at the same time
as Walter Kenton?
That's correct.
And at that time,
did Walter Kenton know
the KS lesions on your face and arms
were caused by AIDS?
Definitely.
I told all the partners.
How did Walter Kenton treat you
after you told him you had AIDS?
Every time he'd
come in contact with me,
he'd get this look on his face.
I refer to it
as the "Oh, God" expression.
As in, "Oh, God, here comes
that woman with AIDS."
Thank you, Ms. Benedict.
No more questions, Your Honor.
Ms. Benedict, how did you
contract the AIDS virus?
Through a transfusion.
I lost a lot of blood
giving birth to my second child.
So, in other words, in your case,
there was no behavior on your part
which caused you
to be infected with the virus.
It was something you were unable to avoid.
Isn't that correct?
I guess.
Thank you.
But I don't consider myself any different
from anyone else with this disease.
I'm not guilty.
I'm not innocent.
I'm just trying to survive.
Thank you, Ms. Benedict.
No further questions at this time,
Your Honor.
You may step down,
Ms. Benedict.
Beyond noticing the marks on his face,
were there other things about
his appearance, Miss Burton,
that made you suspect
that Andrew had AIDS?
Well, he was getting thinner,
and he seemed very tired sometimes,
but he was working so hard.
Still, I felt something was wrong,
and I can't believe
that they're trying to pretend
that they didn't notice anything.
Objection.
Just answer the question, please.
Have you ever felt discriminated
against at Wyant-Wheeler?
Well, yes.
In what way?
Well,
Mr. Wheeler's secretary, Lydia,
said that Mr. Wheeler
had a problem with my earrings.
Really?
Apparently Mr. Wheeler
felt they were
too "ethnic" is the word she used,
and she told me
that he said he would like it
if I wore something a little less garish,
a little smaller, and more...
"American."
What'd you say?
I said, "My earrings are American.
They're African-American."
Let's have order, please.
Thank you. No more questions.
Miss Burton,
weren't you recently promoted?
Yes, I'm in charge
of the paralegal department.
Congratulations on your unfettered
ascendancy at Wyant-Wheeler.
Well, I don't know if I'd go so far
as to call it unfettered.
I don't understand.
How do you explain
the promotion of an obviously
intelligent, articulate,
qualified African-American woman
in a firm which practices
discrimination
as wantonly and consistently
as you and Mr. Beckett claim?
I can't explain it.
Could it be
that these...
instances of discrimination
are in fact misunderstandings...
that have been blown
completely out of proportion?
I think counsel tends
to oversimplify the issue somewhat.
Well, thank you, Miss Burton.
I'll... take that note
under consideration.
How's the trial going?
Excuse me?
It's a great case.
I saw you on television.
I'm a law student at Penn.
Oh.
How you doing?
I'm all right. How are you?
Saw me on TV?
Yeah.
It's a good school, Penn.
What year are you in?
Second.
Listen, I just want to tell you,
this case,
it's tremendously important,
and I just wanted to let you know
I think you're doing a fantastic job.
Hey.
Thank you.
Look, when you graduate,
you give me a call.
All right. Thank you.
Thank you very much.
Listen, Joe?
Yeah?
Would you like to have a drink with me?
I just finished a game
and I could use a beer, you know?
Uh, no, I can't. My wife is...
I don't pick up people
in drugstores every day.
What? You think I'm gay?
Aren't you?
What's the matter with you?
I look gay to you?
Do I look gay to you?
Joe, relax.
What do you mean, relax?
You know, I ought to kick
your faggoty little ass.
Take it as a compliment. Jeez.
You know, that is exactly
the kind of bullshit
that makes people hate your little...
faggoty ass.
You want to try and kick my ass, Joe?
Asshole.
No, you're the asshole, buddy.
Please continue, Miss O'Hara.
We were going crazy
looking for this complaint.
I felt like I was in the Twilight Zone.
Mr. Beckett was
screaming at everybody
and he just...
he looked so freaky
and Mr. Kenton kept saying,
"You lost the Highline complaint?"
And he called Mr. Wheeler,
and all of a sudden,
Jamey comes in
with the complaint in his hand.
He says,
"It was in central files, Andy."
Central files?
Yes, central files is a place
where paperwork is sent
when cases are closed.
Well, Jamey ran it
over to the court just in time,
and everybody just stood there,
completely wasted,
and Mr...
and Mr. Beckett
just kept saying,
"I'm sorry. Sorry.
I don't understand this."
Thank you, Miss O'Hara.
No further questions
at this time, Your Honor.
All right. Mr. Miller?
May I?
Certainly.
Thank you.
You okay?
Yes.
You want a glass of water
or something?
No.
Was Andy a good boss?
Yes.
He was very sweet.
How would you characterize
his work as an attorney?
How would I know?
I just worked for him.
Excuse me, Your Honor,
but is this for the record?
Mr. Miller, perhaps you should
return to counsel's table.
Yes, sir.
Miss O'Hara?
Yes?
Were you aware,
at any time,
of any problems that
the senior partners had
with the quality of Andrew's work
prior to this missing file episode?
No.
No, I wasn't.
Thank you.
No more questions, Your Honor.
Is Andrew Beckett the kind of lawyer
who misplaces crucial documents?
Not to my knowledge.
No.
Mr. Collins, if you wanted to
make a lawyer look incompetent,
would this be a good way
of going about it?
Hiding an important document
maybe for a few hours,
and then making it look like
the responsible lawyer misplaced it?
Why would Mr. Wheeler and
the others behave so outrageously?
Because they found out Andy was sick?
He's not answering the question.
Perhaps.
We have lawyers who've
had heart attacks, ulcers,
prostate cancer, leukemia.
No one sandbagged them.
Did you have something to do
with this file being lost
accidentally on purpose?
Objection.
I'll rephrase.
Did you have anything to do
with this file being misplaced?
Absolutely not.
Are you a homosexual?
What?
Answer the question. Are you a homo?
Are you a faggot? You know, a punk,
queen, pillow biter, fairy?
Bootie snatcher, rump roaster?
Are you gay?
Objection.
Order. Order.
Where did this come from?
Suddenly counsel's
attacking his own witness?
Mr. Collins' sexual orientation
has nothing to do with this case.
Please have a seat, Miss Conine.
Would you approach the bench,
Mr. Miller?
Could you kindly share with me
exactly what's going on inside your head,
because at this moment,
I don't have a clue.
Your Honor,
everybody in this courtroom
is thinking about...
sexual orientation,
you know, sexual preference,
whatever you want to call it.
Who does what to whom
and how they do it.
I mean, they're looking
at Andrew Beckett.
They're thinking about it.
They're looking at Mr. Wheeler,
Miss Conine, even you, Your Honor.
They're wondering about it.
Trust me,
I know they're looking at me
and thinking about it,
so let's just get it out in the open.
Let's get it out of the closet,
because this case
is not just about AIDS, is it?
So let's talk about
what this case is really all about.
The general public's hatred,
our loathing,
our fear of homosexuals,
and how that climate
of hatred and fear
translated into the firing
of this particular homosexual,
my client, Andrew Beckett.
Please have a seat, Mr. Miller.
Very good.
In this courtroom,
Mr. Miller, justice is blind
to matters of race,
creed, color, religion,
and sexual orientation.
With all due respect, Your Honor...
we don't live in this courtroom,
though, do we?
No, we don't.
However, as regards to this witness,
I'm going to sustain
the defense's objection.
How many weeks at a time
would you be out to sea
without stopping at port?
Oh, anywhere from two weeks
to several months.
Any women on board?
Uh, not when I was in the Navy.
So, during these long voyages,
months at a time out to sea,
no women in sight,
hundreds of hardworking,
robust young men
in the prime of their lives,
at the peak of their natural
appetites and desires,
their God-given
hormonal instincts,
anything going on?
Going on? Like what?
Like two sailors down below
making flippy-flop.
Objection.
Mr. Miller.
We had one guy like that.
You haven't ruled
on my objection, Your Honor.
Go on, Mr. Miller.
You had one guy "like that."
You mean a homosexual?
He strutted around quarters naked,
trying to get everybody to notice him.
Made everyone sick.
He was destroying our morale,
so we let him know this kind
of behavior was not acceptable.
How'd you do that?
What'd you do?
Wrote him a letter?
We stuck his head in a latrine
after 10 of us had used it.
You taught him a lesson, didn't you?
Yes, we did.
Just like firing Andrew Beckett
taught him a lesson.
Objection.
I withdraw.
You were aware when you
worked with Melissa Benedict
that she had AIDS, is that correct?
She didn't try to conceal it.
So you are aware of the difference
between a bruise and a lesion.
Is that correct?
Beckett told me he had been
hit by a racquetball,
and I believed him.
Didn't you try to avoid contact
with Mrs. Benedict
after you found out she had AIDS?
She says, and I quote, that you...
"were repulsed by her,
you avoided her."
Is that correct?
I felt, and I still feel nothing
but the deepest sympathy
and compassion for people like Melissa
who contracted this terrible disease
through no fault of their own.
Don't move, now.
Oh... Okay.
Boy... it's not going through.
We may have to flush it out again.
Oh...
The vein's closed.
We've got to call Barbara.
Nurse Ratchett.
Wait a minute.
Yeah, tell her to come over.
Look, I've...
There's so much stuff
I need to get done.
Can we...can we just skip
the treatment for tonight?
No. No, we are not
skipping this treatment.
It's my arm, and it's my treatment,
and I say skip it.
Well...
You know something?
Hmm?
That stuff is saving your life.
What's the matter with you tonight?
Close the law book.
Will you just...
Eh?
The least you can do...
is look at me,
and give me a little of your time, man.
Got it?
You are worried...
we don't have very much
time left, now, aren't you?
No. No.
Well, I'll tell you what I'm gonna do.
I'm going to start planning
my memorial service.
I'm going to start preparing
for the inevitable.
Maybe you should think about it.
No...
No, no, no.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
I've got a better idea.
Hi, Andrew. Hi, Miguel.
Hey, hey!
Oh, Joe Miller, counselor.
My wife, Lisa.
Are you Lisa?
Nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you too.
Miguel, Lisa.
You look wonderful!
Lisa, Joe.
Miguel's sister, Maria.
Do you care for something to drink?
I'll take care of Joe, Maria.
Okay.
Thanks very much.
You're looking, uh... alive tonight!
Oh, I had a blood transfusion,
and I feel great.
Ah! So, you like it? I'm a lawsuit.
You get it? I'm a lawsuit.
It's not bad. It's not bad.
Law... suit.
What are you drinking?
Wine is good.
Can I have some of the red, please?
So we've got to get to this Q & A
sometime tonight, you know?
Sure. Just one problem.
I'm at a party right now.
Yes, fine. Whatever.
No, no, we'll get to it,
just later, that's all.
Thank you.
Hi, Joe Miller.
Do I know you?
Mona Lisa.
Ah... Uh, lawsuit.
Nice. Have fun.
Okay, Miguel, thank you.
Ah, thank you.
Sure.
Congratulations, counselor.
Congratulations?
You've survived what I assume
to be your first gay party intact.
Let me tell you something, Andrew.
When you're brought up the way I am,
the way most people are in this country,
there's not a whole lot of discussion
about homosexuality,
or what do you call it...
alternate lifestyles.
As a kid you're taught
that queers are funny,
queers are weird,
queers dress up like their mother,
that they're afraid to fight,
that they're a danger to little kids,
and that all they want to do
is to get into your pants.
And that pretty much sums up
the general thinking out there,
if you want to know the truth about it.
Thank you for sharing that with me.
All right, well,
let's go over this testimony.
We've got a big day on Monday.
Okay. First I'll ask you,
"Can you describe the circumstances
in which you joined the firm
Wyant, Wheeler, Hellerman,
Tetlow & Brown?"
Miller...
do you ever pray?
Andrew, that is not the answer
to the question...
but, yes, I pray.
What do you pray for?
What do you mean?
I pray.
I pray that, uh...
I don't know,
I pray that my...
baby is healthy.
I pray that my wife
made it through the delivery.
I pray the Phillies win the pennant.
Now, can we go through these questions?
Number one, "Can you
describe the circumstances
in which you joined the firm
Wyant, Wheeler, Hellerman,
Tetlow & Brown?"
Can you do that for me?
There's a possibility I won't be around
to see the end of this trial.
Yes, I've considered that.
I've made some provisions
in my will for some charities.
Miguel will need a lawyer.
I know it's not your area.
I know a good probate lawyer.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Now, can you describe
the circumstances
in which you joined the firm
Wyant, Wheeler, Hellerman,
Tetlow & Brown?
Do you mind this music?
Do you like opera?
I am not that familiar
with opera, Andrew.
Oh, this is my favorite aria.
It's Maria Callas.
It's Andrea Chenier.
Umberto Giordano.
This is Madeleine.
She's saying how...
during the French Revolution,
the mob set fire to her house...
And her mother died...
saving her.
She says, "Look!
"The place that cradled me
is burning...
I'm alone."
Do you hear the heartache
in her voice?
Can you feel it, Joe?
Now in come the strings,
and it changes everything.
The music, it fills with a hope.
Now, it'll change again. Listen.
Listen.
"I bring sorrow to those who love me."
Oh... Oh, that single cello.
"It was during this sorrow
that love came to me."
"A voice filled with harmony."
"It said, live still."
"I am life."
"Heaven is in your eyes."
"Is everything around you
the blood and the mud?
"I am divine.
"I am oblivion.
"I am the god...
"that comes down
from the heavens to the earth
"and makes of the earth a heaven.
"I am love.
I am love."
Well, uh...
Hey...
Geez, I...
I better get out of here.
Lisa's, uh...
I told her that, you know...
Uh, I'll look over the Q & A.
No, you're ready. You're ready.
Um...
Jesus...
Huh... God.
Yes, baby.
Oh, I love you, little Larice.
Place your left hand on the Bible.
Raise your right hand.
Do you swear to tell the whole truth,
and nothing but the truth,
so help you God?
I do.
Please be seated.
Andrew...
can you describe the circumstances
in which you joined the firm
Wyant, Wheeler, Hellerman,
Tetlow & Brown?
Wyant-Wheeler
aggressively recruited me.
They were the most
prestigious firm in Philadelphia,
full of opportunity,
and I was impressed with the partners.
Including Charles Wheeler?
Particularly Charles.
What impressed you about him?
He was the kind of lawyer
I thought I wanted to be.
And what kind of lawyer is that?
Possessed of an encyclopedic
knowledge of the law,
a razor-sharp litigator, genuine leader,
gifted at bringing out
the very best in others,
an awesome ability to illuminate
the most complex of legal concepts
to a colleague, to a courtroom,
to the man in the street.
The kind of person who can
play three sets of tennis,
but doesn't sweat.
Underneath an elegant surface,
he has an adventurous spirit.
So in the years you worked
at Wyant-Wheeler,
did you ever tell
Charles Wheeler you were gay?
No, I...I didn't.
Why not?
You don't bring your personal life
into a law firm.
You're not supposed to have
a personal life, really.
Anyway, I did plan to tell
Charles eventually,
but then this...
oh, something happened
at the racquet club
about three and ha... three years ago...
Somebody started telling some jokes.
What do you call a woman
who has PMS and ESP
at the same time?
I don't know, Roger,
what do you call her?
A bitch who knows everything.
Sounds like someone I know.
Hey, Walter, how does
a faggot fake an orgasm?
He throws a quart of hot yogurt
on your back!
That reminds me of the hairdresser...
How'd that make you feel?
Relieved...
that I never told him I was gay.
Just very relieved.
All right.
Are you a good lawyer, Andrew?
I'm an excellent lawyer.
What makes you an excellent lawyer?
I love the law.
I know the law.
I excel at practicing.
What do you love about the law, Andrew?
I... many things.
Uh...
What I love the most about the law?
Yes.
Is that every now and again,
not often, but occasionally,
you get to be a part of...
justice being done.
That really is...
quite a thrill when that happens.
Thank you, Andrew.
You said earlier you...
aspire to be the kind of person
who had an adventurous spirit.
Is that correct?
Something like that.
Do you take risks?
In my work, yes, calculated risks.
You have to.
Did your doctor ever tell you
to reduce stress?
That... long hours
and stressful working conditions
might damage the immune system
and speed up your illness?
My doctor mentioned the impact AIDS...
Excuse me...
My doctor mentioned the impact stress
could have on the immune system.
Have you ever been to
the Stallion Showcase Cinema
on 21 st street?
I...I've been to... that...
I've been to that theater...
three times in my life.
What kind of movies do they show there?
Gay movies.
Gay pornographic movies?
Yes.
Objection, Your Honor.
Your honor, this line of questioning
is vital to the issue of credibility.
Let's, uh...
Let's see where this is going.
Continue, counselor.
Do men have sex with each other
in that theater?
Some men.
Have you ever had sex
with anyone in that theater?
I'm Robert.
Andy.
Yes.
Once.
When?
Approximately what year
did that event take place?
I guess it was, uh...
1984.
'84, '85.
Were you aware in 1984, '85
that there was a fatal disease
out there called AIDS,
and that you could contract it
through... sexual activity?
I'd heard of some...
I'd heard of a thing, uh...
the gay plague, the gay cancer.
We didn't know how you could get it,
or that it killed you.
Do you need a break, Mr. Beckett?
No...
No, I...I could use some water, though.
John, could you bring Mr. Beckett
some water please?
While you were employed at Wyant-Wheeler,
you did everything you could
to make sure no one knew that
you were an active homosexual.
Is that correct?
No.
That's not correct.
I never lied about it.
As a homosexual,
one is often forced
to conceal one's sexuality.
Isn't that right?
In some circumstances, yes.
Isn't it true that you've spent your life
pretending to be something you're not,
so much so that the art
of concealment and dishonesty
has become second nature...
Your Honor, I object.
I'll withdraw it, Your Honor.
Mr. Beckett, were you living with...
Miguel Alvarez...
in 1984 or '85
when you had your...
anonymous sexual encounter
in the porn theater?
Yes.
So you could have infected him,
isn't that right?
Miguel has not been infected.
You didn't answer my question.
You could have infected
Mr. Alvarez at that time.
Is that correct?
Yes.
You've testified
that the lesions on your face
were visible to the people
that you worked with, correct?
That's right.
And it's your contention
that when the partners
were made aware of the lesions,
that they leapt to the conclusion
that you had AIDS, and they fired you.
Is that correct?
As painful as it is
to accuse my former colleagues
of such reprehensible behavior,
it is the only conclusion
I could come to.
Do you have any lesions
on your face at this time?
One...
Here, right by my ear.
Your Honor, may I approach the witness?
Yes, you may.
Remembering that you're under oath,
answering truthfully,
can you see the lesions
on your face in this mirror
from three feet away?
Answering truthfully.
Well, I...at the time I was fired,
I had four lesions,
and they were much bigger.
Could you answer the question, please?
Well, uh, no.
No, I can't really see it.
No.
No more questions, Your Honor.
I think this would be a good time
to break for today.
We can reconvene in the morning.
I hate this case.
Your Honor, may I have,
uh, five minutes in redirect?
Mr. Beckett, can you
go on for five minutes?
Three minutes.
Yes. Yes.
May I borrow your mirror, please?
Andrew...
do you have any lesions
on any part of your body
at this time that resemble
the lesions you had on your face
at the time that you were fired?
Yes.
On my tor...torso.
Your torso.
If it please the court,
I would like to ask Andrew
to remove his shirt,
so that, you know, everyone here
could get an accurate idea
of what we're talking about.
Objection!
Your Honor, it would
unfairly influence the jury.
Your Honor, if Andrew was forced
to use a wheelchair due to his illness,
would the defense ask him
to park it outside
because it would
unfairly influence the jury?
Come on, we're talking about AIDS,
we're talking about lesions.
Let's see what we're talking about.
I'll allow it.
Mr. Beckett, would you please
remove your shirt?
My God, what a nightmare.
He asked for it.
Andrew...
can you see the lesions
on your chest in this mirror?
Yes.
Thank you.
Do you swear to tell the whole truth,
and nothing but the truth,
so help you God?
I do.
Please be seated.
Mr. Wheeler...
were you aware that Andrew Beckett
was suffering from AIDS
at the time of his departure
from Wyant-Wheeler?
No.
For absolute clarity,
did you fire Andrew Beckett
because he had AIDS?
No, I did not fire Andrew Beckett
because he had AIDS.
Mr. Wheeler, can you explain
in a way that leaves no doubt
why you promoted
Andrew Beckett through your firm,
and then, most importantly,
why you eventually asked him to leave?
If, uh, you're the owner
of a major league ball club,
you recruit the hot rookie,
and Andy was tremendously
promising as a young attorney.
Fresh out of Penn.
Crackerjack.
That's why we went after him,
that's why we hired him,
and that's why we stuck
with him year after year.
Why did you give him
opportunity after opportunity?
Well, when you groom someone
the way we groomed Andy,
nurturing him,
lavishing all kinds
of special treatment on him,
you make quite an investment.
We were waiting for the promise
to kick in and deliver,
but, uh, ultimately we could
no longer ignore the gap
between the reality and the promise.
Thank you, Mr. Wheeler.
No more questions
at this time, Your Honor.
Mr. Miller?
Objection.
Your Honor, objection!
All right, Mr. Miller.
That'll be sufficient.
Mr. Wheeler, you are magnificent.
You are... you are my hero.
Andrew is right.
You are the greatest.
Are you gay?
Objection.
How dare you.
Witness will kindly answer.
No, I am not a homosexual.
Isn't it true that when you realized
Andrew Beckett, your golden boy,
your future senior partner,
was gay and had AIDS,
it drove a stake of fear
right through your heterosexual heart?
Remembering all the hugs
and the handshakes,
the intimate moments in the sauna,
the friendly pats on the backside
that you and Andrew exchanged...
like I've exchanged sometimes.
It made you say,
"My God,
what does this say about me?"
Objection, Your Honor.
The witness will please
respond to the question.
Mr. Miller, you may tap dance
around me all you wish
with your innuendoes
and locker-room fantasies,
but the truth still remains
that your client
worked when he wanted to work,
telling us what he thought
we needed to know
about who he really was.
Andy insisted on bending the rules,
and his work suffered
tremendously in the long run
as a result of that.
Well, you explain this to me
like I'm a six-year-old, Mr. Wheeler,
because I just don't get it.
Who makes these rules
that you're talking about, huh?
You?
Read your Bible, Mr. Miller,
Old and the New Testament.
Pretty valuable rules in there.
Excu...excuse me.
Andrew?
Excuse me. I...I can't s...
Agh!
Excuse me. Andy!
For chrissakes, somebody get a doctor!
Turn over now.
Call an ambulance, please.
Right away!
An ambulance, please!
Let him breathe!
Please make room for him.
It's not working!
It is not working!
No, it is making it worse!
Did you notice any changes whatsoever
in Andrew's appearance
over the course of the year
leading up to his termination?
Yes... I did.
Were these changes for the better
or for the worse?
Sometimes for the better,
but generally, they were for the worse.
Mr. Seidman, what did you
think caused these changes
in Andy's appearance?
I was... afraid.
I suspected Andy had AIDS.
Order. Order!
Thank you.
Your witness.
Miss Conine?
Mr. Seidman,
did you share your suspicions
with Mr. Wheeler
or any of the other managing partners
at any time before the decision
to fire Andrew Beckett was made?
No. No, I didn't.
I didn't mention it to anyone,
not even Andy.
I didn't even give him
a chance to talk about it...
and I think I'm going to regret that...
for as long as I live.
Any more questions, Miss Conine?
That's all, Your Honor.
Now, they are saying
that he wasn't a good lawyer,
he was mediocre,
and the fact that they gave him
the most important lawsuit
that they ever had
for one of their most important clients,
now, they say that
that doesn't prove anything
because that was just a test.
What'd they call it?
A carrot?
Yeah, what's up, doc?
To see if he would rise to the occasion.
Okay, okay,
so say I've got to send a pilot
into enemy territory,
and he's gonna be flying a plane
that costs $350 million.
Who am I gonna put in that plane?
Some rookie who can't cut the grade
because I wanna see
if he can rise to the challenge?
Or am I gonna give that assignment
to my best pilot,
my sharpest,
my most experienced, my top gun,
the very best I've got?
I just don't get that.
Would somebody please explain it to me...
like I'm a six-year-old.
Juror number six.
I agree.
Juror number seven.
Juror number eight.
Agree.
Juror number nine.
I agree.
Juror number ten.
I disagree.
Juror number 11.
I agree.
Juror number 12.
Agree.
Have you awarded any damages?
Yes, Your Honor, we have.
For back pay and loss of benefits,
we award $143,000.
For mental anguish and humiliation,
we award $100,000,
and for punitive damages,
we award $4,782,000.
You may record the verdict.
Everyone remain seated
until the jury is removed.
How could they do that?
This trial is now concluded.
Ha-ha!
Congratulations!
We'll strain ourselves
getting a reversal on this.
We'll get started in the morning.
Well, that's that.
Congratulations, Mr. Miller.
We'll see you at the appeal.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
Well done.
Oh, man...
Thanks a lot.
I'll see you at the hospital.
Okay.
Oh, Mr. Miller.
Hi, how you doing?
Do you know where his room is?
Just down the hall.
The one off the lounge.
Thanks.
If he leaves the hospital,
which is unlikely,
don't expect him to be remotely
like he was before this crisis.
He's lost the vision in his right eye,
and because of the CMV,
he will not regain his vision.
Next door to the right.
The CMV has ravaged his body...
Hi. Congratulations.
Hey, Joe.
Way to go!
Man of the hour.
Hey, Joe.
Hi.
We are so grateful to you.
You were wonderful.
Thank you so much.
Can I take that?
Yeah. I brought some...
cheese and... stuff.
Oh, wonderful. Thanks.
How you doing?
Mm.
What do you call a thousand lawyers
chained together
at the bottom of the ocean?
I don't know.
A good start.
Mm-hmm.
Excellent work, counselor.
I thank you.
It was great working with you...
counselor.
Well, I'd better go.
Y... yeah. Sure thing.
I'll see you later?
Thanks for stopping by.
I'll see you again.
Well, I'll...
keep it on ice for you.
See you.
Joe, I just want to say thank you.
We really appreciate it.
We'll see you again?
All right.
He's a fighter.
We just want to get him home.
Thank you, Joe.
Oh, sorry.
What do you call a thousand lawyers
chained together
at the bottom of the ocean?
A good start?
Very amusing.
I'll see you tomorrow, buddy, okay?
See you tomorrow.
God bless you, Andy.
Good night, son.
Try to get some rest, okay?
Okay...
I love you, Andy.
I love you too, Dad.
See you first thing tomorrow.
It's okay.
Don't worry, Don.
See you tomorrow.
It's okay.
Come on, sweetheart. Come on.
It's all right. It's all right.
It's okay. It's all right.
Don't worry about it.
Good night, my angel.
My sweet boy.
Let me help you.
Miguel...
I'm ready.
Hello.
Joe, it's Miguel.
Look at my boy.